const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department by his parents with a complaint of loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, the child is found to be active with no visible signs of dehydration. What is the management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"ORS 100-200ml after each loose motion","bool":true},{"option":"I/V ringer lactate","bool":false},{"option":"I/V normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"No fluids","bool":false},{"option":"Mineral water","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following negligences refers to defective hospital care and equipment, incompetent employees, and failure to maintain the standards of care?","answers":[{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":true},{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Third party negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 28-year-old male comes to the emergency room with complaints of rising fever for the past 4 days, which was initially low grade and has become high grade. He also complains of generalized weakness and abdominal pain. On general examinations, the vitals are; blood pressure: 100/60 mm Hg, pulse: 64 beats per minute, temperature:  103 Â°F, respiratory rate: 22 breaths per minute. The systemic examination is unremarkable. What is the patient most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Brucellosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the emergency department with complaints of fever, fatigue, and headache for the past 10 days. He is now experiencing agitation and hallucination, with aggressive behavior. History suggests that he suffered a dog bite 4 weeks ago. On examination, he is found to have excessive salivation, hyperreflexia, and spasticity. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Psychosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false},{"option":"Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is the mediator responsible for causing fever in systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS)?","answers":[{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":true},{"option":"Bradykinin","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"An 18-year-old boy, who has migrated from Quetta to Karachi, presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, abdominal pain, lethargy, and reduced appetite since the past week. History suggests that he is working at a tandoor (roti) shop for the last 3 months and lives in an unhygienic environment. He drinks tap water. On examination, a faint, salmon-colored, maculopapular rash is noticed on his trunk. Apart from a complete blood count (CBC), what is the next most appropriate test to diagnose his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Urine for culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Stool for ova and parasite","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis A and E antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Blood for culture and sensitivity","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 6-year-old child is brought by her mother with the complaint of severe agitation and disturbed sleep at night for the past week. On inquiry, the child admits she has severe perianal itching at night. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":true},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the screening test of choice for HIV in neonates?","answers":[{"option":"HIV PCR","bool":true},{"option":"CD4 count","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":false},{"option":"HIV p24 antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Northern Blot","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 12-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with complaints of fever and abdominal cramps, followed by diarrhea.  The diarrhea was initially watery but now contains blood and mucus. Which organism is the cause of diarrhea and dysentery?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella spp","bool":true},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A child presents to the clinic with fever and convulsions. The child was bitten by a dog 3 months ago. Which of the following samples must be obtained to confirm a diagnosis of rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Urine","bool":false},{"option":"Nail clippings","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Stool","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"When are leading questions asked?","answers":[{"option":"When an expert has been called","bool":false},{"option":"During examination-in-chief","bool":false},{"option":"When the judge wishes to ask questions","bool":false},{"option":"A hostile witness is being questioned","bool":true},{"option":"When the witness is of unsound mind","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 20-year-old unconscious male is brought to the emergency room with profuse bleeding from the incised wound on his left wrist. Which of the following types of consent will be used to treat this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Expressed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Implied consent","bool":true},{"option":"No need of consent","bool":false},{"option":"Oral consent","bool":false},{"option":"Written consent","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following parasites may cause rectal prolapse in children and has barrel-shaped eggs on microscopic analysis?","answers":[{"option":"Histoplasma capsulatum","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiuria","bool":true},{"option":"Ancyclostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":false},{"option":"Loa Loa","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"During a police encounter, a dacoit is shot dead. Who will carry out the investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Medico-legal officer of the area","bool":false},{"option":"The magistrate","bool":true},{"option":"The police","bool":false},{"option":"The panchas","bool":false},{"option":"The coroner","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A doctor receives 5 cases of cholera together at his private clinic in Lahore. He should report these cases to which of the following authorities?","answers":[{"option":"District nazim","bool":false},{"option":"Local police station","bool":false},{"option":"District police station","bool":false},{"option":"Area magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"District health authorities","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits the microtubule formation in roundworm, pinworm, and hookworm infections and can eradicate worm infestation?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Thiabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 24-year-old farmer comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of difficulty in opening his mouth. He also has a small wound in the heel of his right foot. On examination, generalized body stiffness is found. He is rushed to the emergency room for further evaluation of suspected tetanus. Which of the following is an important step in the management of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Give intravenous metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Give prophylactic heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Administer adsorbed tetanus toxoid (TT)","bool":false},{"option":"Perform endotracheal intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Administer human tetanus immunoglobulin (HTIG)","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A young patient comes to the clinic with a complaint of abdominal pain for 2 days, accompanied by a fever for the past one day. Laboratory results show increased total leukocyte count (TLC) and raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR). The doctor suspects the acute inflammation of the intestine. Which of the following is responsible for his symptoms and acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Lipoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-24","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-23","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-1","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of diarrhea. On examination, he is seen to have rectal prolapse. His stool analysis shows barrel-shaped eggs with plugs at each end. Which one of the following nematodes is most likely to be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Loa loa","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the drug of choice in cestode infection?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 36-year-old woman, with a known case of HIV infection, has a very low CD4 lymphocyte count and was prescribed treatment. She is non-compliant with her medications and now presents with shortness of breath on exertion and hypoxia. Her chest X-ray reveals fine bilateral infiltrates and the computed tomography (CT) scan reports a bilateral ground-glass appearance. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcal pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs is a preferred prophylactic regimen of malaria in pregnant women?","answers":[{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors may lead to gastrointestinal toxicity, such as pancreatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Didanosine","bool":true},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors causes antagonism with zidovudine?","answers":[{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":true},{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A medical man appeared in the court to record his statement. After recording, he feels that the court might misinterpret his observations, which may likely lead to a miscarriage of justice. What can he do in this scenario to ensure that justice is served right?","answers":[{"option":"Record his protest","bool":false},{"option":"Volunteer a statement","bool":true},{"option":"Withdraw his statement","bool":false},{"option":"Modify his statement","bool":false},{"option":"Make an appeal","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Conduct money is given in a case involving which offense?","answers":[{"option":"Murder","bool":false},{"option":"Shoplifting","bool":false},{"option":"Homicide","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false},{"option":"Divorce","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Koplik's spots are characteristic enanthem of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Macules","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following laboratory tests can help make a presumptive diagnosis of varicella-zoster virus infection?","answers":[{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Tzanck smear","bool":true},{"option":"Serologic tests","bool":false},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drug is the preferable treatment in the case of neurocysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazaole","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"In the court of law, during the recording of evidence, leading questions are only allowed during cross-examination. Which of the following is the only other condition where the prosecution can ask leading questions?","answers":[{"option":"Re-examination","bool":false},{"option":"Volunteering a statement","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical examiners testimony","bool":false},{"option":"Privileged communication","bool":false},{"option":"Witness is declared hostile","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 55-year-old male presents with fever, weight loss, and cough with hemoptysis for the past 2 weeks. His sputum is acid-fast bacillus (AFB) smear-positive. What is the likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Maculopapular rash and posterior auricular lymphadenopathy are the characteristic signs of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken Pox","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following anti-leprotic drugs can cause pink to brownish-black discoloration of the skin with an itchy-dry texture?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Moxifloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A young patient presents to the clinic with complaints of acute watery diarrhea without abdominal pain, along with vomiting. The stool is rice-watery in nature. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Norvovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Amebiasis (E. histolytica)","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs is effective against the exo-erythrocytic form of malarial parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following clinical signs indicates sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Heart rate > 85 breaths per minute","bool":false},{"option":"Partial pressure of oxygen < 80 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia < 140 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory rate < 16 breaths per minute","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cell count > 12,000 mmÂ³ or <4000 mmÂ³","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"SchÃ¼ffnerâs dots are the intracytoplasmic granules found, within infected red cells, due to an infection with which of the following plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Crescent-shaped gametocytes are found in infection by which of the following plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 15-year-old boy comes into the emergency department. He has had a history of fever for the last 2 weeks, initially, low-grade 100 F, followed by high-grade with severe abdominal pain. His blood culture is done as an outpatient is positive for Salmonella typhi with sensitivity to azithromycin and imipenem-cilastatin. An X-ray of the abdomen, erect and supine, shows gas under the right diaphragm. What is the most common site of gut perforation in enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending colon perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Jejunum perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Ileal perforation","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 10-year-old-child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of headache, neck stiffness, and fever. Bacterial culture was done, and Neisseria meningitidis were isolated. What is the probable diagnosis of this case?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 19-year-old-girl presents to the outpatient department with complaints of severe watery diarrhea. Upon history taking, she told about consuming shellfish at a party the previous night. Her bacterial cultures show colonies of a comma-shaped bacterium. What is the causative organism of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella toxin","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following factors indicates a poor prognosis of Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Virus?","answers":[{"option":"Liver necrosis and cerebral haemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatomegaly and splenomegaly","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and gastrointestinal disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Myalgia and vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalopathy and respiratory distress","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A girl got injured with a rusty nail by walking around barefoot. What organism is she at the risk of being affected with?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium septicum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is true about dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue virus belongs to the togavirus family","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue is transmitted by the Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"The vaccine contains inactivated dengue virus","bool":false},{"option":"Humans are the reservoirs of dengue virus","bool":true},{"option":"Hematemesis is indicative of dengue fever","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient complains of having recurrent malarial infection after recovering from it once, caused by Plasmodium ovale and Plasmodium vivax. Which form of these Plasmodium species is responsible for the relapses?","answers":[{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Metacryptozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Gametozoites","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which form of plasmodium is inoculated by the Anopheles mosquito into humans?","answers":[{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Metacryptozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Gametozoites","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is an example of criminal negligence?","answers":[{"option":"Not counting the gauzes used in operation","bool":false},{"option":"Not giving proper post-operative care","bool":false},{"option":"Surgically removing the fine eye instead of the diseased","bool":true},{"option":"Not attending to a labor patient","bool":false},{"option":"Giving injection on the wrong side or the wrong route","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A student is in charge of the urogenital system and needs to decide who should be screened for gonorrhea. Out of the following options, which of the following groups of people does not need to be screened?","answers":[{"option":"Transgenders","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous drug abusers","bool":false},{"option":"Sex workers","bool":false},{"option":"Doctors treating gonorrhea patients","bool":true},{"option":"Clients of sex workers","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following indicates sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with documented infection","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with lactic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with blood pressure < 90 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with severe hypotension","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs is administered to a pregnant woman diagnosed with Chlamydial urethritis?","answers":[{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin V","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A convict is called numerous times to attend a trial in court, but he fails to appear. Ultimately the court orders a summons to be put outside his house. Which of the following describes a summons?","answers":[{"option":"A letter that can only issued by the magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"Letter to a person to appear in court for evidence or any other reason","bool":true},{"option":"A rectangular scripture to call upon an entity for assistance","bool":false},{"option":"A fee tendered to cover court expenses","bool":false},{"option":"A warrant to arrest the person and present them in the court","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following species of plasmodium causes malignant tertian malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"There is a patient with a clear indication of sepsis. To treat the resultant hypotension, intravenous fluids are administered, but they do not improve the condition significantly. What is the next step of treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Identification and removal of source of infection","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressors such as norepinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Surgical debridement","bool":false},{"option":"Inoculation of antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of broad-spectrum antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs directly inhibits human-immunodeficiency virus (HIV) reverse transcriptase without phosphorylation?","answers":[{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false},{"option":"Nevirapene","bool":true},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A doctor is called in sessions court as a witness. During cross-examination, he utters an indecent remark on the defense counsel, which is brought to the knowledge of the judge who gives minimum punishment to the doctor. Which of the following would it be?","answers":[{"option":"Detaining him in the court till rising of the court for the day","bool":true},{"option":"Warning in writing with copy to the employer","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 10 only","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 100 only","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 50 only","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A young male develops a high-grade fever intermittent in nature and occurring every 48 hours. Later on, his laboratory report reveals that he has vivax malaria. Which subtype fever does he have?","answers":[{"option":"Quotidian fever","bool":false},{"option":"Quartan fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant tertian fever","bool":false},{"option":"Relapsing fever","bool":false},{"option":"Tertian fever","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Among all the types of leprosy, which of the following has a good prognosis and may even heal itself?","answers":[{"option":"Borderline tuberculoid","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient presents with complaints of fever and body ache for the past two days. What is the best initial test for the diagnosis of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) and c-reactive protein (CRP) tests","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue nonstructural protein 1 (NS1) test","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue serology","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive test for diagnosis of liver hydatid cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) of the abdomen","bool":true},{"option":"Serology","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Fine needle aspiration (FNA)","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound of the abdomen","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following organisms causes diarrheal disease in almost 100% of the children by the age of five years?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":true},{"option":"Candida","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A certain tapeworm uses two elongated sucking grooves to attach to the intestinal wall. It may lead to vitamin B-12 deficiency, resulting in megaloblastic anemia. Which of the following worms is this?","answers":[{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"The present-day societies have high expectations from medical professionals regarding their ideal ethical practice. The broader guidelines can be learned from the subject of medical ethics. What does this subject deal with?","answers":[{"option":"Research ethics should be made mandatory","bool":false},{"option":"Implied contract and its details","bool":false},{"option":"Interpersonal relationships are the basic requirement","bool":false},{"option":"Confidentiality of patient record as an ideal ethical practice","bool":false},{"option":"Moral values to be observed by medical professional in their practice","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of these diseases is characterized by the presence of 'Negri bodies'?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which vaccines are given at birth according to the EPI schedule?","answers":[{"option":"Penta + OPV","bool":false},{"option":"OPV + BCG + hep B","bool":true},{"option":"OPV 0 + BCG","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV 1","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumo + BCG","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the term used for diarrhea that lasts for at least 14 days and has no blood?","answers":[{"option":"Amebic dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Acute diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent diarrhea","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 25-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of watery diarrhea for the past few days. He also tells that he has recently traveled to Hunza. Which of the following pathogens is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Enteropathogenic  E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Enteroinvasive E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic E. coli","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is a protease inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Efavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Tinidazole is better than metronidazole due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"It surpasses first pass effect","bool":false},{"option":"It is not active against anerobic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"It has longer half-life","bool":true},{"option":"It is used in the pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"It has better absorption","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Other than its anthelmintic activity, which of the following does tinidazole have activity against?","answers":[{"option":"Aerobic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Obligate aerobe","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative cocci","bool":false},{"option":"Anaerobic bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"Gram positive cocci","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs acts by increasing the GABA activity?","answers":[{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A man presents to the outpatient department with a bite wound on his arm. He has cats and rats in her house. On examination, the bite marks look more likely of a rat. Which of the following animals will not transmit rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Mongooses","bool":false},{"option":"Donkey","bool":true},{"option":"Rat","bool":false},{"option":"Cat","bool":false},{"option":"Bat","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Leaving gauze in abdominal surgery comes under which negligence?","answers":[{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":true},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate misconduct","bool":false},{"option":"3rd party negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the term used for a letter or a document issued by a court for the person under penalty to attend the court?","answers":[{"option":"Subpoena","bool":true},{"option":"Inquiry","bool":false},{"option":"Proof","bool":false},{"option":"Perjury","bool":false},{"option":"Evidence","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which type of evidence establishes a fact or at least presumption of the fact on examination?","answers":[{"option":"Hearsay evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Documentary evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Direct evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Prima facie","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is used for the treatment of syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Acyclovir","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following leads to the activation of the coagulation cascade in SIRS?","answers":[{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue factor","bool":true},{"option":"Interferon alpha","bool":false},{"option":"IL-1 and IL-6","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is used for giardiasis and gives rise to metallic taste as its side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 34-year-old presents with abdominal pain, bloating, nausea, and vomiting for the past few days. A complete blood count reveals eosinophilia. Small bowel obstruction is present. A nasogastric (NG) tube is inserted. Which of the following drugs is the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Piperazine","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of ciprofloxacin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of topoisomerase I","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of topoisomerase IV","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of transpeptidase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitor of cell wall synthesis","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A man with a known case of HIV presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, weight loss, and fatigue. He is diagnosed with the case of mycobacterium avium complex. What is the treatment used for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Rifabutin as it prevents dissemination","bool":false},{"option":"Clarithromycin, rifabutin and ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin and clarithromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is the best treatment for hydatid cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole and praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR and albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Albendazole 400 mg for 3 months","bool":false},{"option":"Cyst resection","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 6-year-old child took his father's pistol to show to his friends but the pistol accidentally went off. One of his friends got injured. Under the law, the child is considered as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Unfit to plead","bool":false},{"option":"Diminished responsible","bool":false},{"option":"Not sane","bool":false},{"option":"Not criminally responsible","bool":true},{"option":"Guilty","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the most common non-inflammatory diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 35-year-old diabetic patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever associated with rigor and chills and increased frequency of urine. There are no other significant findings. What is the most probable cause?","answers":[{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Viral fever","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following causes bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Megaloblastic anemia caused by pyrimethamine can be reversed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cyanocobalamin","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha tocopherol","bool":false},{"option":"Leucovorin","bool":true},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient in the hospital was on the ventilator and got treated for an illness with clindamycin, ethambutol, and some other antibiotics. He then got extubated and was started on meropenem 10 days ago. Two days ago he presented with watery diarrhea suggesting a C. difficile infection. How will this condition be managed?","answers":[{"option":"IV metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Stop meropenem and give oral metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Stop all antibiotics and send stool sample for ova and parasite","bool":false},{"option":"IV vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Oral vancomycin","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice in a patient who has foul-smelling diarrhea along with nausea, vomiting, and abdominal pain?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Clindamycin","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"ELISA done for an HIV patient is stored for how many days?","answers":[{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4Â°C for 3 day upto 7 days","bool":true},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4Â°C for 4 day upto 8 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4Â°C for 2 day upto 6 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4Â°C for 1 day upto 5 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4Â°C for 5 day upto 9 days","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Unilocular cyst seen in brain CT is a characteristic of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Enterococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"According to  Integrated Management of Neonatal & Childhood Illness (IMNCI), which of the following is the danger sign?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal behavior","bool":false},{"option":"High grade fever","bool":false},{"option":"Convulsing now","bool":true},{"option":"Uprolling of eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Froth from mouth","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of maraviroc?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of glycoprotein 16","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive inhibition of HIV polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase transfer strand inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Fusion of virion to T cell","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which glycoproteins (gp) are used by the HIV to gain entry inside the cell?","answers":[{"option":"gp 120 and gp 12","bool":false},{"option":"gp 24 and gp 17","bool":false},{"option":"gp 160 and gp 41","bool":false},{"option":"gp 24 and gp 120","bool":false},{"option":"gp 120 and gp 41","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the term used for the disease whose number of cases are occurring infrequently, haphazardly, and at different times and places?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperendemic","bool":false},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":true},{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A female patient presents to the gynecology department with a complaint of vaginal discharge. What is the non-infectious cause of vaginal discharge?","answers":[{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical irritants","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the gold standard test for salmonella typhi?","answers":[{"option":"Typhi dot test","bool":false},{"option":"Widal test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Stool culture","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following test is used to measure the efficacy of highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART)?","answers":[{"option":"CD3 count","bool":false},{"option":"p24 levels","bool":false},{"option":"CD24 count","bool":false},{"option":"p40 levels","bool":false},{"option":"Viral RNA","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with a cough, runny nose, and red eyes. On examination, koplik spots are found in the buccal mucosa. What is the patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A child presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, fatigue, and severe itching in the rash. On examination, the papulovesicular rash is seen on the child's trunk and extremities. Which stain or smear can be used for the diagnosis of the organism involved?","answers":[{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Methylene blue","bool":false},{"option":"Tzanck smear","bool":true},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":false},{"option":"Ethanol","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Strawberry cervix is seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Zidovudine belongs to which class of group?","answers":[{"option":"Protease inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Non-nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase inhibitor","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Dying deposition has more weightage than dying declaration due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"It is taken under oath","bool":false},{"option":"Magistrate time is precious","bool":false},{"option":"It is recorded by magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"Given in the presence of accused","bool":true},{"option":"Remain valid after recovery","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient has a positive test for salmonella typhi. Which disease is he suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What should be the target central venous pressure (CVP) in sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"10-15 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"8-12 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"1-5 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"6-10 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 12 mm Hg","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the drug of choice for vaginal candidiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Flucytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Cystatin","bool":false},{"option":"Fluconazole","bool":true},{"option":"Nystatin","bool":false},{"option":"Miconazole","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"The CBC report of dengue hemorrhagic fever will show which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Neutropenia and leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopenia and thrombocytopenia","bool":true},{"option":"Neutropenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"What is the drug of choice for visceral leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Liposomal amphotericin B","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which enzyme is required to make double-stranded DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":true}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient presents to the gynecology department with a lesion in a genital area. On examination, it is found to be a sexually transmitted genital ulcerative disease in which irregular margins of a lesion are seen. The patient is also seen to have tender lymphadenopathy and diagnosis of chancroid is made. Chancroid is caused by which organism?","answers":[{"option":"Lactobacillus","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus ducreyi","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 2.5-year-old child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of vomiting and loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, no sunken eyes were found and the skin turgor test is normal. What is the appropriate management for this child?","answers":[{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose","bool":true},{"option":"1/5 normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"1/2 normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"1/3 normal saline","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, and swelling in the jaw. The mother further adds the swelling is painful when the child drinks citrus fruit juices. On examination, swelling is noticed to be of parotid gland enlargement. What is the child suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is the likely cause of pneumonia in a patient who previously had a splenectomy?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus auerus","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A swimmer developed diarrhea and abdominal cramping after the swimming competition. Which organism is the cause of his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Trichomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 20-year-old boy presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of fever after returning from his trip. The doctor prescribed him chloroquine. Which other drug should also be prescribed to him?","answers":[{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Co-trimoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A girl presents to the outpatient department with lethargy and an ulcer in her right foot. Her laboratory results show hemoglobin 6 mg/dL. What is the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoide","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":true}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A teenager is hospitalized with a history of a dog bite 2 weeks ago. He is found to be anxious, irritable, and drooling at the mouth. What is the appropriate treatment for him?","answers":[{"option":"Pass a nasogastric tube for feeding and medications","bool":false},{"option":"Provide a comfort care in a quiet environment","bool":true},{"option":"Empiric antibiotic therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Start him on ribavirin therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Pass an endotracheal tube for ventilation","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A patient with a history of AIDs and tuberculosis 2 years back is admitted for the surgery of appendicitis. What precautions should be taken?","answers":[{"option":"Single ward with respiratory precautions","bool":true},{"option":"Single ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with standard precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"Single ward with standard precautions","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Zieman dots with basket forms and occasional band forms of plasmodium are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 26-year-old, pregnant woman is diagnosed with gonorrhea. There is a previous history of anaphylactic shock on the administration of amoxicillin. Which of the following drugs is given as a single dose?","answers":[{"option":"Cefixime","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Spectinomycin","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs will be added to the gonorrhea treatment regimen for the prevention of chlamydia?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Spectinomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Cefexime","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is gold standard for the diagnosis of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Blood film for microscopic examination of the parasite","bool":true},{"option":"Immunochromatographic rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for malarial antigens","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of chloroquine for sensitivity analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to detect plasmodium DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid screening card agglutination test for antibody detection","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes forms dsDNA from ssRNA?","answers":[{"option":"Protease","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase","bool":false},{"option":"Endonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Ribonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"At what CD4+ count of a patient with human immunodeficiency virus do AIDS-defining illnesses emerge?","answers":[{"option":"< 250 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 150 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 50 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 100 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 200 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"Which of the following is used routinely in clinics for the diagnosis of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Immunochromatographic rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for malarial antigens","bool":true},{"option":"Administration of chloroquine for sensitivity analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to detect plasmodium DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid screening card agglutination test for antibody detection","bool":false},{"option":"Blood film for microscopic examination of the parasite","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2021","question":"A 29-year-old man presents with complaints of fever, which was initially low-grade and then became high-grade, headache, and abdominal discomfort. His vitals showed blood pressure 180/100 mmHg, and a pulse of 65 beats/min. What is the most likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}]}]
export default arr